Guide to the Stanford University Football Motion Picture Collection
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University football motion picture collection
1937-2013
1963-2013
SC1033
Stanford University. Department of Athletics.
1.5 Linear feet 39 motion pictures
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Materials were acquired from varied sources.
Information about Access
Access: Materials are open to research use; some items may require reformatting prior to patron use.
Associated Materials
Additional football films and videorecordings may be found in this repository in the following collection: Stanford University, Department of Athletics, Physical Education and Recreation, Media Relations, records (SC0367).
Scope and Contents note
The motion picture films, primarily 16mm reels, date from 1937-1982 with most of them falling between 1963-1982; they include games, highlights, and clips of Darrin Nelson and John Elway. Videorecordings and DVDs date from 1941 to 1993 and include games or parts of games, highlights, a film on John Elway, and some personal footage from the 1941 Rose Bowl.
Access Terms
Elway, John, 1960-; Nelson, Darrin.; Football.; Videorecordings.
Collection Contents
- Motion pictures
  - Rose Bowl, 1941; V309; 1 videotape(s)
    mostly family films which include less than a minute of Rose Bowl game and more parade
  - Big Game, third quarter, 1952; V034; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
    Football--big game
  - Big Game, V074; 1 videotape(s) (VHS)
  - Stanford vs USC, 1968; V117; 3 videotape(s)
    Plunkett, Jim--Simpson, O.J.
  - Stanford at Arizona State, October 9; V160; 4 videotapes (3/4 inch)
  - Stanford vs. Oregon State, V161; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
  - Rose Bowl (Ohio State), 1971; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
    - Rose Bowl (Ohio State)--highlights, 1971; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
    - Rose Bowl (Ohio State)--highlights, 1971; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
  - Big Game, 1982; V245; 1 videotape(s) (Betamax)
  - John Elway, the Winning Touch, 1987; V081; 1 videotape(s) (VHS)
    Elway, John
  - Glyn Milburn highlight reel, 1991; V162; 1 videotape(s) (U-matic)
    Milburn, Glyn
  - Great Moments of the Big Game, 1991; V069; 1 videotape(s) (VHS)
    Albert, Frankie.--Brodie, John.--Elway, John, --Lansford, Mike.--Plunkett, Jim; Football--big game
  - Stanford vs. Arizona, 1992 Oct 17; V159; 3 videotapes (3/4 inch)
  - Blake vs. Jordan + Breck, both away - white jerseys [football?], V310; 1 videotape(s) (VHS)
  - Orange Bowl (Virginia Tech), 2011 Jan 3; 1 optical disc(s) (DVD)
  - Rose Bowl (Wisconsin), 2013 Jan 1; 1 optical disc(s) (Blu-ray)